EMILIE GERBER WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT

${}^{\smile}$

emiliegerberharris@gmail.com

emiliegerber.com

503.475.3520

♀ Seattle,WA

in /in/emiliegerber

nemilieq

SUMMARY

I am a Seattle-based web developer with a not-so-traditional tech background. In my past lives I've been an Account Manager, a Marketing Coordinator and a Pilates Instructor. I strive to create meaningful web applications that are functional, informative, and aesthetically pleasing for the user drawing from my past experiences. As a creative thinker and problem solver, I can close the gap between clients and companies.

EDUCATION

General Assembly

Web Development 2016

Portland State University

Bachelor of Arts Painting, Drawing Printmaking 2008

SKILLS

SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, Ruby, HTML5, CSS3

Frameworks: Node.js, Express, Rails, AngularJS

Database Tools: SQL, PostgreSQL, Sequelize

Other: jQuery, AJAX, JSON, Bootstrap, Heroku, SalesForce, Drupal, Google Analytics, Adobe Creative Suite

PROJECTS

What's That?

A product scanner app that translates scientific ingredient language into simple terms. This was a group project with 4 members and won the 2nd place as well as the Code4Impact award at AngelHack Seattle, April 2016. Technology: Node.js, Angular.js, Swift, JavaScript, ExpressJS

Wino911

This helps you find a place that serves wine and provides directions from your current location.

Technology: JavaScript, Node.js, ExpressJS, Postgres, Sequelize

APIs: Google Places, Google Directions, Forecast.io

Stuck in the Mud

Stuck in the Mud is a dice game where two players compete for the highest score.

Technology: HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery

EMPLOYMENT

General Assembly

Seattle, WA

Web Developement Immersive · Mar 2016 to Jun 2016

Attended a 12-week full-time immersive web development program where I learned to develop full-stack web applications using various languages, frameworks, and libraries with a strong focus on the MEAN stack. Worked on group and individual projects using test driven development strategies and technologies.

Conscious Body Pilates

Seattle, WA

Pilates Instructor · Jan 2015 to Mar 2016

Instructed private and group classes primarily working with clients with injuries.

Seattle Times

Seattle, WA

Marketing & Research Coordinator · Jul 2015 to Jan 2016

Planned and promoted the Seattle Times LiveWire event series using Social Media and working with partners from local 500 companies.

Measurement Technology NW & ECS

Seattle, WA

Marketing Coordinator · Nov 2014 to Jul 2015

Developed marketing strategies and campaigns targeting prospective clients. Evaluated campaign reports and use data for future optimization. Managed website content using Drupal and Google Analytics for SEO improvement. Created marketing materials using Adobe tools.

Pacific Interpreters

Portland, OR

Regional Account Manager NW · Feb 2008 to Nov 2014

Managed customer accounts with an average of \$700,000 monthly revenue. Expanded existing accounts by upselling new products and services. Increased customer revenue by 20% in 2012. Worked with internal IT team on implementation of Salesforce.